[
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
      "question": "Which one is used for online meeting?",
      "options": ["Google Meet", "Gmail", "Excel", "None of above"],
      "correct_answer": "Google Meet"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
      "question": "Google Classroom is used for -------?",
      "options": [
        "Online learning",
        "Searching website",
        "Physical learning",
        "None of above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Online learning"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
      "question": "To start an online meeting which one is not essential?",
      "options": [
        "Internet connection",
        "Computer/Smart phone",
        "Web Browser",
        "Microsoft Word"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Microsoft Word"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
      "question": "Which one is not a presentation software?",
      "options": [
        "PowerPoint Presentation",
        "Prezi",
        "Google Slide",
        "Microsoft Word"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Microsoft Word"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
      "question": "Which one is not possible using Google Classroom?",
      "options": [
        "Assignment submission",
        "Give certificate",
        "Give a grade",
        "Written test"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Give certificate"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "Why are headers and footers used in MS-Word?",
      "options": [
        "To enhance the overall appearance of the document",
        "To mark the starting of a page",
        "To make large document more readable",
        "To allow page headers and footers to appear on document when it is printed"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "To allow page headers and footers to appear on document when it is printed"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "If you want to keep track of different editions of a document which features will you use?",
      "options": ["Editions", "Versions", "Track Change", "All of above"],
      "correct_answer": "All of above"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "Borders can be applied to.",
      "options": ["Cells", "Text", "Paragraph", "All of above"],
      "correct_answer": "All of above"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "To get to the ‘Symbol’ dialog box, click on the --------- Tab and choose ‘Symbol’",
      "options": ["Home", "Layout", "Insert", "View"],
      "correct_answer": "Insert"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "The Greater Than sign (>) is an example of --operator.",
      "options": ["Arithmetic", "Logical", "Conditional", "Greater"],
      "correct_answer": "Logical"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "In Excel, rows are labeled as --------------",
      "options": ["etc.", "1,2,3 etc.", "A1, A2, etc.", "$A$1, $A$2, etc."],
      "correct_answer": "1,2,3 etc."
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "In Excel, which one denotes a range from B1, through E5",
      "options": ["B1-E5", "B1:E5", "B1 to E5", "B1$E5"],
      "correct_answer": "B1:E5"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "MS Excel stands for ----------------------------",
      "options": [
        "Mieromax Excel",
        "Management Excel",
        "Microsoft Excel",
        "Microsoft Word"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Microsoft Excel"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "--is the best alternative to MS excel offered by Google Inc",
      "options": [
        "Google Slides",
        "Google Sheets",
        "Google Files",
        "Google Keep"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Google Sheets"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "MS Excel file can NOT be directly exported as-------------",
      "options": ["PDF", "TXT", "PPT", "CST"],
      "correct_answer": "PPT"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "A file that contains one or more worksheets to organize data is known as--------------",
      "options": ["Workbook", "Excel book", "Datasheet", "Spreadsheet"],
      "correct_answer": "Workbook"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "Which of the following is not Available on the ruler of MS Word Screen?",
      "options": ["Tab stop box", "Center indent", "Left indent", "Right indent"],
      "correct_answer": "Center indent"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "Times new roman, Cambria, Arial are examples of---",
      "options": ["Font face", "Clipart", "Smart art", "Themes"],
      "correct_answer": "Font face"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "Which term is not related to the font?",
      "options": ["Font grammar", "Font color", "Font size", "Font face"],
      "correct_answer": "Font grammar"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "------refers to back the object to one level or to all objects.",
      "options": ["Align", "Rotate", "Send to back", "Bring to front"],
      "correct_answer": "Send to back"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "You can use the ……… to insert Symbol",
      "options": [
        "Font dialog box",
        "Text dialog box",
        "Paragraph dialog box",
        "Symbol dialog box"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Symbol dialog box"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "Press ………. to start the presentation from the beginning.",
      "options": ["F5", "F6", "F7", "F8"],
      "correct_answer": "F5"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "……… lowers the selected text below the baseline and changes the selected text to a smaller font size. If a smaller size is available",
      "options": ["Superior script", "Upper font", "Subscript", "Footer"],
      "correct_answer": "Subscript"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "Which term is related to increasing or decreasing the space between characters?",
      "options": ["Page number", "Spacing", "Header", "Footer"],
      "correct_answer": "Spacing"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "The ability to combine name and address with a standard document is called?",
      "options": [
        "Document formatting",
        "Database Management",
        "Mail merge",
        "Form letter"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Mail merge"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "How To Use Format Painter Multiple?",
      "options": [
        "By Click on Lock Format Painter Icon",
        "Format Painter Cannot Be Used Multiple Times",
        "By Double Click on The Format Painter Icon",
        "None of Above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "By Double Click on The Format Painter Icon"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "We can change the thickness of a line from –",
      "options": ["Line Thick", "Line Height", "Line width", "Line Style"],
      "correct_answer": "Line Style"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "In MS-Word for what does ruler help?",
      "options": [
        "To set indents",
        "To change page margins",
        "To set tabs",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 1",
  
      "question": "In Microsoft Word shortcut key CTRL + W is used for",
      "options": [
        "Update the current web page",
        "Close the current window",
        "Open the Print dialog box",
        "None of this"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Close the current window"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি Search Engine নয়?",
      "options": ["Google", "Bing", "Google Chrome", "Yahoo"],
      "correct_answer": "Google Chrome"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি Social Media নয়?",
      "options": ["Google Meet", "Facebook", "Likedin", "Tweeter"],
      "correct_answer": "Google Meet"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি Online storage নয়?",
      "options": ["Dropbox", "Onedrive", "Google Drive", "Zoom"],
      "correct_answer": "Zoom"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি Email ID নয়?",
      "options": [
        "bteby@mail.com",
        "btebcbt@gov.bd",
        "@btebcbt.com",
        "122bteb@gmail.com"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "@btebcbt.com"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি Input Device নয়?",
      "options": ["Scanner", "Monitor", "Mouse", "Barcode reader"],
      "correct_answer": "Monitor"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি Typing Software?",
      "options": ["Sutonnymj", "Bijoy", "Kalpurush", "Nikush"],
      "correct_answer": "Bijoy"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি Numeric Character?",
      "options": ["H", "K", "&", "7"],
      "correct_answer": "7"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি Anti-Virus নয়?",
      "options": ["Linux", "Norton", "Avest", "Nood32"],
      "correct_answer": "Linux"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি ¯’স্থায়ী storage Device নয়?",
      "options": ["RAM", "Cash Memory", "SSD", "CPU R এরster"],
      "correct_answer": "SSD"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি System Unit এর অংশ নয়?",
      "options": ["Processor", "RAM", "Hard disk drive", "Flash drive"],
      "correct_answer": "Flash drive"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "Projector enable করার Keyboard command কি?",
      "options": [
        "Windows Key + P",
        "Windows Key + V",
        "Windows Key + C",
        "Windows Key + R"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Windows Key + P"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "A4 সাইজের কাগজ কোনটি?",
      "options": ["8.5”X11”", "8.27”X11.69”", "8.5”X14”", "8.5”X11.5”"],
      "correct_answer": "8.27”X11.69”"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি Document Paste করার Keyboard Command?",
      "options": ["Ctrl + P", "Ctrl + C", "Ctrl + V", "Alt + V"],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl + V"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি page break এর keyboard command?",
      "options": ["Ctrl + Break", "Ctrl + End", "Ctrl + Enter", "Ctrl + Home"],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl + Enter"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি MS Word এর File extension",
      "options": [".dot", ".py", ".exe", ".docx"],
      "correct_answer": ".docx"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "একই Formatting অন্য একাধিক Text এর উপর apply করতে নিচের কোন অপশনটি ব্যবহার করতে হয়?",
      "options": [
        "Copy and Paste old text",
        "Copy, paste then edit",
        "Use format painter",
        "Use clipboard"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Use format painter"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোন Line Spacing টি অগ্রহনযোগ্য",
      "options": ["Multiple", "Double", "Triple", "Single"],
      "correct_answer": "Triple"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "কোনটি Excel এর Valid data type নয়?",
      "options": ["Date/time", "Label", "Charter", "Number"],
      "correct_answer": "Charter"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "Excel Window এর কোন Area তে Value ও Formula লেখা যায়?",
      "options": ["Formula bar", "Menu bar", "Title Bar", "Standard toolbar"],
      "correct_answer": "Formula bar"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "Row নং 5 ও 6 এর Column C হতে E পর্যন্ত Cell গুলো হতে Largest number টি Select করার জন্য-",
      "options": ["=large(c5:e6)", "=large(c5:e5)", "max(c5:e5)", "max(c5:e6)"],
      "correct_answer": "=large(c5:e6)"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "MS – Excel এ ভাগশেষ বের করার জন্য কোন function ব্যবহার করা হয়?",
      "options": ["mod()", "round()", "fact()", "div()"],
      "correct_answer": "mod()"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "MS – Powerpoint এ তৈরী করা কোনও file এর extension হলো",
      "options": [".ppt", ".pptx", ".xlsx", ".docx"],
      "correct_answer": ".pptx"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "MS- Powerpoint এ কোন প্রেজেন্টেশনে নতুন ¯স্লাইড প্রবেশ করার অপশন হল",
      "options": [
        "Home > Slides > new slide",
        "Home > Slides > layout",
        "A, B DfqwU",
        "কোনটিB bq"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Home > Slides > new slide"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "MS- Powerpoint এ কোন প্রেজেন্টেশনে নতুন ¯স্লাইড প্রবেশ করার শর্টকাট হল",
      "options": ["Ctrl+n", "Ctrl+m", "Shift_n", "Alt+n"],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl + m"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 2",
      "question": "MS- Powerpoint এ নতুন প্রেজেন্টেশন তৈরীর শর্টকাট হল?",
      "options": ["Ctrl+n", "Ctrl+m", "Shift_n", "Alt+n"],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl + n"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "Which of the following is not a valid version of MS Office?",
      "options": ["Office Vista", "Office XP", "Office 2007", "Office 2016"],
      "correct_answer": "Office Vista"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "The key F12 is used to open a –",
      "options": [
        "Save dialog box",
        "Open Dialog box",
        "Save as dialog box",
        "Close dialog box"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Save as dialog box"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "Portrait and Landscape are-",
      "options": ["Page border", "Paper size", "Page layout", "Page orientation"],
      "correct_answer": "Page orientation"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "To apply center alignment to a paragraph, we can press-",
      "options": ["Ctrl+ S", "Ctrl+ E", "Ctrl+ C+A", "Ctrl+ c"],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl+ E"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "Which is the text-styling feature of MS Word -",
      "options": ["Word Color", "Word Art", "Word Font", "Word Fill"],
      "correct_answer": "Word Art"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "What is the shortcut-key for a manual line break -",
      "options": ["Ctrl+ Enter", "Alt+ Enter", "Shift+ Enter", "Space+ Enter"],
      "correct_answer": "Shift+ Enter"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "Which of the following is not word processing software",
      "options": ["Paint", "Easy word", "MS word", "Word Perfect"],
      "correct_answer": "Paint"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "Ctrl+ Page Down is used to -",
      "options": [
        "Moves the cursor one page down",
        "Moves the cursor one paragraph down",
        "Moves the cursor one line down",
        "Moves the cursor one screen down"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Moves the cursor one page down"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "To select the entire column in MS Excel, press",
      "options": [
        "Ctrl+ C",
        "Ctrl+ arrow key",
        "Ctrl+ Shift+ Down Arrow",
        "Ctrl+ S"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl+ Shift+ Down Arrow"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "Which one shortcut key is used to close the Spreadsheet",
      "options": ["Ctrl+ S", "Ctrl+ arrow key", "Ctrl+ W", "Ctrl+ C"],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl+ W"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "Give me an example of a cell address",
      "options": ["11 25", "A21", "41A", "911"],
      "correct_answer": "A21"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "You accidentally erased a record in the sheet. What command can be used to restore it immediately?",
      "options": ["Insert", "Copy", "Replace", "Undo"],
      "correct_answer": "Undo"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "What is the symbol for multiplying?",
      "options": [">", "*", "│", "/"],
      "correct_answer": "*"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "What is the keyboard shortcut used to go home tab",
      "options": ["Ctrl+ work", "Ctrl+ Arrow key", "Alt+ Home", "Ctrl+ Home"],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl+ Home"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "With which of the following do all formulas in Excel start",
      "options": ["=", "*", "$", "/"],
      "correct_answer": "="
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "A spreadsheet contains",
      "options": ["Columns", "Rows and columns", "Rows", "None of above"],
      "correct_answer": "Rows and columns"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "NOT, AND, OR, and XOR are which type of operator",
      "options": [
        "Affirmative operator’s",
        "Arithmetic operators",
        "Relational operator’s",
        "Logical operator"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Logical operator"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "Which of the following sections does not exist in a slide layout",
      "options": ["Titles", "Lists", "Animations", "Charts"],
      "correct_answer": "Animations"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "A new presentation can be created from",
      "options": [
        "Form existing presentation",
        "Blank presentation",
        "Form design Template",
        "All of above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "All of above"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "What is the best way to create another copy of a slide?",
      "options": [
        "From insert menu choose Duplicate slide",
        "Click the slide then press Ctrl+ A and paste in new slide",
        "Redo everything on a new slide that you had done on the previous slide",
        "None of above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "From insert menu choose Duplicate slide"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "To insert a hyperlink in a slide",
      "options": [
        "Both b & c",
        "Press Ctrl+ K",
        "Choose insert>> Hyperlink",
        "Hyperlinks can’t be inserted in slides"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Both b & c"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "Want your logo in the same position on every slide automatically? Insert on the",
      "options": [
        "Template master",
        "Notes master",
        "Slide master",
        "Handout master"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Slide master"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "What is the full name of NTFS?",
      "options": [
        "New technology file system",
        "New technology Format system",
        "New taxonomy file system",
        "New taxonomy file service"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "New technology file system"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "One byte is equal to how many bits",
      "options": ["4 bits", "8 bits", "12 bits", "16 bits"],
      "correct_answer": "8 bits"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "Where are saved files stored in the computer?",
      "options": ["RAM", "Cookies", "Cache", "Hard disk"],
      "correct_answer": "Hard disk"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "What is windows?",
      "options": [
        "An application system",
        "An operation system",
        "An operating system",
        "None of above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "An operating system"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 3",
      "question": "What is 'Facebook'",
      "options": [
        "Social network",
        "Family Network",
        "City Network",
        "Wide Network"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Social network"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "A device that holds a disk is called a",
      "options": ["Drive", "ROM", "Memory", "RAM"],
      "correct_answer": "Drive"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which of the following panes is not available in Task pane",
      "options": ["Getting Started", "Clip Art", "Search result", "Word Art"],
      "correct_answer": "Search result"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which type of software would you use to make the computer perform a specific task such as writing a letter or drawing a picture?",
      "options": [
        "System software",
        "Utility software",
        "Operating software",
        "Application software"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Application software"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which of the following units represents the largest amount of data",
      "options": ["kilobytes", "Terabytes", "Gigabytes", "Megabytes"],
      "correct_answer": "Terabytes"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "A file that the user can open and is called",
      "options": ["Application", "Document", "Program", "Data"],
      "correct_answer": "Document"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which of the following allows you to select more than one slide in a presentation",
      "options": [
        "Alt+ Click each slide",
        "Alt+ Drag each slide",
        "Ctrl+ Click each slide",
        "Esc+ Click each slide"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl+ Click each slide"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "What PowerPoint feature will you use to apply motion effects to different objects of a slide",
      "options": [
        "Animation Scheme",
        "Slide Design",
        "Animation object",
        "Slide Transition"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Animation Scheme"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which one consists of instructions that control the computer",
      "options": ["Programs", "List", "Keyboard", "File"],
      "correct_answer": "Programs"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Presentation designs regulate the formatting and layout for the slide and are commonly called",
      "options": ["Design templates", "Blueprints", "Placeholders", "Templates"],
      "correct_answer": "Templates"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Dos and some versions of Unix are examples of",
      "options": [
        "Old Fashion",
        "Graphical User Interface",
        "Command-line Interface",
        "Parallel Interface"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Command-line Interface"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which of the following is not a term of MS Excel",
      "options": ["Cell", "Documents", "Rows", "Columns"],
      "correct_answer": "Documents"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which is the shortcut key to highlight the entire column",
      "options": ["Ctrl+ C", "Ctrl+ Enter", "Ctrl+ Page Up", "Ctrl+ Space Bar"],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl+ Space Bar"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "What is a cookie?",
      "options": [
        "A file created by the browser each time its user accesses a website",
        "A virus placed on a computer by spyware to delete directories",
        "An image file that expands to fill a browser’s cache",
        "A text file placed on a client by a web server to track user performances"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "A text file placed on a client by a web server to track user performances"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which is an example of a formula",
      "options": ["=a1+a2", "=add(a1:a2)", "A1+A2", "Sum(a1:a2)"],
      "correct_answer": "=a1+a2"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which one of the following memories is used to store data permanently?",
      "options": [
        "Secondary memory",
        "Primary memory",
        "Cache memory",
        "Register"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Secondary memory"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which tab in MS Word can be used to change character size and typeface?",
      "options": ["View", "Home", "Page Layout", "Insert"],
      "correct_answer": "Home"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Older printers were typically connected to computers through a",
      "options": ["NIC Card", "Serial Port", "Jack", "Parallel Port"],
      "correct_answer": "Parallel Port"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "What port is a fast connection that is more flexible than traditional serial and parallel ports?",
      "options": ["Serial", "Parallel", "USB", "Ethernet"],
      "correct_answer": "USB"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which of the following will you use to find the highest number in a series of numbers",
      "options": [
        "Maximum (b1:B3)",
        "Max(B1:b3)",
        "High(b1:b3)",
        "Highest(b1:b3)"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Max(B1:b3)"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Modem speed is measured in",
      "options": [
        "Bits per second",
        "Bytes per second",
        "Bits per second",
        "Bytes per minute"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Bits per second"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which command will you use in PowerPoint if you need to change the color of different objects without changing content?",
      "options": [
        "Color scheme",
        "Design Template",
        "Font Color",
        "Object color"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Color scheme"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "What is Wi-Max",
      "options": [
        "Super Computer",
        "Client PC",
        "PDA",
        "Wireless Internet Technology"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Wireless Internet Technology"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Thesaurus tool in MS Word is used for",
      "options": [
        "Synonyms and Antonyms",
        "Spelling suggestions",
        "Translate",
        "None of These"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Synonyms and Antonyms"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "What is another name for a program?",
      "options": ["Procedure", "Software", "Topology", "Utilities"],
      "correct_answer": "Software"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which is an example of a function",
      "options": ["=add(A3:A4)", "=deduct(A3:A4)", "=(A3:A4)", "=Sum(A3:A4)"],
      "correct_answer": "=Sum(A3:A4)"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "To use a microphone for input on your computer, you must install a",
      "options": ["Aural Card", "Acoustic Card", "Sound Card", "NIC Card"],
      "correct_answer": "Sound Card"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "The term dots per inch (dpi) refers to a printer's",
      "options": ["Resolution", "Speed", "Output", "Colors"],
      "correct_answer": "Resolution"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "The key F7 opens a",
      "options": [
        "Spelling and grammar check box",
        "Save dialog box",
        "Open dialog box",
        "Close dialog box"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Spelling and grammar check box"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "The most commonly magnetic device is",
      "options": ["Hard disk", "RAM", "DVD", "ROM"],
      "correct_answer": "Hard disk"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which is the built-in defragment utility in Windows?",
      "options": ["File defragment", "Disk defragment", "Folder", "Windows"],
      "correct_answer": "Disk defragment"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 4",
      "question": "WWW stands for?",
      "options": [
        "World Whole Wed",
        "World Wide Web",
        "Web World Wide",
        "Wide World Web"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "World Wide Web"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 4",
      "question": "Which of the following are components of Central Processing Unit (CPU)?",
      "options": [
        "Arithmetic logic unit, Control unit",
        "Arithmetic logic unit, Mouse",
        "Arithmetic logic unit, Integrated Circuits",
        "Control unit, Monitor"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Arithmetic logic unit, Control unit"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 4",
      "question": "Full form of URL is",
      "options": [
        "Uniform Registered Link",
        "Uniform Recourse Link",
        "Uniform Recourse Locator",
        "Unified Recourse Link"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Uniform Recourse Locator"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 4",
      "question": "For what location are the 1st Computer instruction available on boot up",
      "options": ["CONFIG.SYS", "CPU", "boot.ini", "ROM BIOS"],
      "correct_answer": "ROM BIOS"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 4",
      "question": "What could cause a fixed disk error?",
      "options": [
        "No-CD installed",
        "Bad RAM",
        "Incorrect CMOS setting",
        "Slow Processor"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Incorrect CMOS setting"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 4",
      "question": "Which with respect to a network interface card, the term 10/100 refers to",
      "options": [
        "Protocol speed",
        "Megabyte per second",
        "A fiber speed",
        "Minimum and maximum server speed"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Megabyte per second"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 4",
      "question": "Which motherboard form factor uses one 20 pin connector?",
      "options": ["AT", "ATX", "BABY AT", "All of the above"],
      "correct_answer": "ATX"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 4",
      "question": "A hard disk is divided into tracks which are further subdivided into",
      "options": ["Clusters", "Vectors", "Sectors", "Heads"],
      "correct_answer": "Sectors"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 4",
      "question": "Which standard governs parallel communication?",
      "options": ["RS232", "RS-232a", "IEEE 1284", "CAT 5"],
      "correct_answer": "IEEE 1284"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 4",
      "question": "Voltage is measured",
      "options": [
        "In parallel",
        "In series",
        "After breaking the circuit",
        "After checking resistance"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "In parallel"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which of the following is not a valid version of MS Office?",
      "options": ["Office XP", "Office Vista", "Office 2007", "None of Above"],
      "correct_answer": "None of Above"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "What is the shortcut key to exit from any application program?",
      "options": ["F12", "Shift + F12", "Alt + F12", "Alt + F4"],
      "correct_answer": "Alt + F4"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which file starts MS Word?",
      "options": ["WinworD.exe", "WorD.exe", "MsworD.exe", "Word2003.exe"],
      "correct_answer": "WinworD.exe"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "What is the default left margin in Word 2003 document?",
      "options": ["1\"", "1.25\"", "1.5\"", "2\""],
      "correct_answer": "1.25\""
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Portrait and Landscape are",
      "options": [
        "Page Orientation",
        "Paper Size",
        "Paper Layout",
        "All of above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Page Orientation"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which of the following is not a font style?",
      "options": ["Bold", "Italics", "Regular", "Superscript"],
      "correct_answer": "Superscript"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "What is the smallest and largest font size available in Font Size tool on the formatting toolbar?",
      "options": ["8 and 72", "8 and 68", "6 and 72", "6 and 68"],
      "correct_answer": "8 and 72"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Selecting text means, selecting?",
      "options": [
        "A word",
        "An entire sentence",
        "Whole document",
        "Any of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Any of the above"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which operation will you perform if you need to move a block of text?",
      "options": [
        "Copy and Paste",
        "Paste and Cut",
        "Cut and Paste",
        "Paste and Delete"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Cut and Paste"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "What are the extension names of Word files supported?",
      "options": ["DOC", "DOCX", "RTF", "All of above"],
      "correct_answer": "All of above"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "How many files are needed to Mail merge?",
      "options": ["3", "2", "4", "1"],
      "correct_answer": "2"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "How do you change column width to fit the contents in MS Excel?",
      "options": [
        "Single-click the boundary to the left to the column heading",
        "Double click the boundary to the right of the column heading",
        "Press Alt and single click anywhere in the column",
        "All of above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Double click the boundary to the right of the column heading"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "You can use the horizontal and vertical scroll bars to",
      "options": [
        "Split a worksheet into two panes",
        "View different rows and columns",
        "Edit the contents of a cell",
        "View different worksheets"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "View different rows and columns"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "You can open the Sort dialog box by choosing Sort from the _____menu",
      "options": ["View", "Format", "Tools", "Data"],
      "correct_answer": "Data"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Except for the _______ function, a formula with a logical function shows the word 'TRUE' or 'FALSE' as a result",
      "options": ["IF", "AND", "OR", "NOT"],
      "correct_answer": "IF"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which shortcut key allows you to edit any cell in MS Excel?",
      "options": ["F2", "F4", "F1", "F5"],
      "correct_answer": "F2"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Each Excel file is called a workbook because",
      "options": [
        "It can contain text and data",
        "It can be modified",
        "It can contain many sheets including worksheet and chart sheets",
        "You have to work hard to create it"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "It can contain many sheets including worksheet and chart sheets"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which types of charts can Excel produce?",
      "options": ["Line graphs", "Pie chart", "Bar chart", "All of the above"],
      "correct_answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "For calculating Average you should use –",
      "options": [
        "Average (cell range)",
        "Max (cell range)",
        "Min (cell range)",
        "Average"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Average"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which of the following describes how to select all the cells in a single column?",
      "options": [
        "Right click on column and select pick form list",
        "Use data – text to columns menu item",
        "Left click on the grey column title button",
        "Pressing Ctrl + A on the keyboard"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Left click on the grey column title button"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "In Microsoft Excel, the maximum column width is –",
      "options": [
        "230 characters",
        "255 characters",
        "250 characters",
        "None of above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "255 characters"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "You can add SmartArt by using which tab?",
      "options": ["Home tab", "Slideshow tab", "Design tab", "Insert tab"],
      "correct_answer": "Insert tab"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "How to add a new slide in your presentation?",
      "options": [
        "Home tab > New Slide",
        "Formatting",
        "Design",
        "Insert > New Slide"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Home tab > New Slide"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "To start Microsoft PowerPoint application?",
      "options": [
        "Click on Start >> Programs >> All Programs >> Microsoft PowerPoint",
        "Hit Ctrl + R then type ppoint. Excel and enter",
        "Click Start >> Run then type power point then press Enter",
        "All of above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "All of above"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "PowerPoint presentations are widely used as",
      "options": [
        "Note outlines for teachers",
        "Project presentation by students",
        "Communication of planning",
        "All of above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "All of above"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which menu provides you options like Animation, Scheme, Custom Animation, Slide Transition?",
      "options": ["Insert tab", "Design tab", "Animation tab", "Slide Show tab"],
      "correct_answer": "Animation tab"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "To insert slide numbers",
      "options": [
        "Insert a text box and select Insert >> Page Number",
        "Insert a text box and select Insert >> Number >> Page Number",
        "Choose Insert >> Slide Number",
        "Insert a new text box and select Insert >> Slide Number"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Choose Insert >> Slide Number"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which of the following font effects is not available in PowerPoint font dialog box?",
      "options": ["Underline", "Shadow", "Emboss", "Strikethrough"],
      "correct_answer": "Emboss"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "To start the slide show of a presentation",
      "options": [
        "Hit F5 key",
        "From Slide Show menu, choose View Show option",
        "From Slide Show menu, choose Rehearse Timing",
        "Both a & b"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Both a & b"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 5",
      "question": "Which of the following is the default page setup orientation of slides in PowerPoint?",
      "options": ["Vertical", "Landscape", "Portrait", "None of above"],
      "correct_answer": "Landscape"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "The process of removing an unwanted part of an image is called?",
      "options": ["Hiding", "Bordering", "Cropping", "Cutting"],
      "correct_answer": "Cropping"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "Ctrl + G is used to",
      "options": [
        "Open Paragraph Dialog box activating Tab",
        "Open page Setup Dialog box activating Go to Tab",
        "Open Find and Replace Dialog box with activating Go to Tab",
        "Open Go to Dialog box."
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Open Find and Replace Dialog box with activating Go to Tab"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "Which operation will you perform if you need to copy a block of text to another place?",
      "options": [
        "Copy and Paste",
        "Cut and Paste",
        "Paste and Delete",
        "Paste and Cut"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Copy and Paste"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "In Excel, cells are labeled as",
      "options": [
        "A, B, C, etc",
        "1, 2, 3, etc",
        "A1, A2, etc",
        "$A$1, $A$2, etc"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "A1, A2, etc"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "Which of these is a search engine?",
      "options": ["FTP", "ARPANET", "Archie", "Google"],
      "correct_answer": "Google"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "Which one is not presentation software?",
      "options": [
        "Power Point Presentation",
        "Prezi",
        "Google Slides",
        "Microsoft Word"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Microsoft Word"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "Which one is not possible using Google Classroom?",
      "options": [
        "Assignment submission",
        "Give Certificate",
        "Give a grade",
        "Written test"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Give Certificate"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "Why are headers and footers used in MS-Word?",
      "options": [
        "To enhance the overall appearance of the document",
        "To mark the starting of the page",
        "To make large documents more readable",
        "To make page headers and footers appear on the document when it is printed"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "To make page headers and footers appear on the document when it is printed"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "If you want to keep track of different editions of a document, which feature will you use?",
      "options": ["Editions", "Versions", "Track Changes", "All of above"],
      "correct_answer": "All of above"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "The greater than sign (>) is an example of _____ operator.",
      "options": ["Arithmetic", "Logical", "Conditional", "Great"],
      "correct_answer": "Conditional"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "In Excel, which one denotes a range from B1 through E5?",
      "options": ["B1-E5", "B1:E5", "B1 to E5", "B1$E5"],
      "correct_answer": "B1:E5"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "______ is the best alternative to MS Excel offered by Google Inc.",
      "options": ["Google Slides", "Google Sheet", "Google Files", "Google Keep"],
      "correct_answer": "Google Sheet"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "Which of the following is not available on the Ruler of MS Word Screen?",
      "options": ["Tab Stop Box", "Center Indent", "Left Indent", "Right Indent"],
      "correct_answer": "Center Indent"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "Times New Roman, Cambria, Arial are examples of ______.",
      "options": ["Font face", "Clipart", "Smart Art", "Themes"],
      "correct_answer": "Font face"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "Which term is not related to the font?",
      "options": ["Font Grammar", "Font Color", "Font Size", "Font Face"],
      "correct_answer": "Font Grammar"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "The _______ button reduces the window to an icon, but the word still remains active.",
      "options": ["Maximize", "Minimize", "Close", "Restore"],
      "correct_answer": "Minimize"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "Press _____ to start a presentation from the beginning.",
      "options": ["F5", "F6", "F7", "F8"],
      "correct_answer": "F5"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "Which term is related to increasing or decreasing the space between characters?",
      "options": ["Page Number", "Spacing", "Header", "Footer"],
      "correct_answer": "Spacing"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "The ability to combine names and addresses with a standard document is called",
      "options": [
        "Document formatting",
        "Database Management",
        "Mail merge",
        "Form letter"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Mail merge"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "How to use Format Painter Multiple Times?",
      "options": [
        "By Clicking on Lock Format Painter Icon",
        "Format Painter Cannot Be Used Multiple Times",
        "By Double Clicking on the Format Painter Icon",
        "None of Above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "By Double Clicking on the Format Painter Icon"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "We can change the thickness of a line from-",
      "options": ["Line Thick", "Line Height", "Line Width", "Line Style"],
      "correct_answer": "Line Style"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "In MS-Word, for what does the ruler help?",
      "options": [
        "To set indents",
        "To change page margins",
        "To set tabs",
        "All of above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "All of above"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "In Microsoft Word, the shortcut key CTRL + W is used for",
      "options": [
        "Update the current web page",
        "Close the current window",
        "Open the print dialog box",
        "None of These"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Close the current window"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "Which one is not online storage?",
      "options": ["Dropbox", "One Drive", "Google Drive", "Zoom"],
      "correct_answer": "Zoom"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set 6",
      "question": "What is the English typing speed in WPM?",
      "options": [
        "Word per minutes",
        "Words per minutes",
        "Words per minute",
        "Word per minute"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Words per minute"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "Search Engine এঁর কাজ কি?",
      "options": [
        "রিসোর্সসমূহ ব্যবহারকারীর কাছে উপস্থাপন করা",
        "ফাইল ডাউনলোড করা",
        "তথ্য কপি করা",
        "কোনটিই নয়"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "রিসোর্সসমূহ ব্যবহারকারীর কাছে উপস্থাপন করা"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি social media?",
      "options": ["Google Meet", "Zoom", "Microsoft Team", "Tweeter"],
      "correct_answer": "Tweeter"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি Online Storage?",
      "options": ["Zoom", "OneDrive", "Meet", "Google Classroom"],
      "correct_answer": "OneDrive"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি সঠিক Email ID ফরম্যাট নয়?",
      "options": [
        "btebcbt@gov.bd",
        "@btebcbt.com",
        "122bteb@gmail.com",
        "bteb@ymail.com"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "@btebcbt.com"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি input device?",
      "options": ["Scanner", "Avro", "Speaker", "Printer"],
      "correct_answer": "Scanner"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি বাংলা Typing Software?",
      "options": ["SutonnyMJ", "Avro", "Kalpurush", "Nikosh"],
      "correct_answer": "Avro"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি Numeric Character?",
      "options": ["H", "K", "&", "7"],
      "correct_answer": "7"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি AntiVirus নয়?",
      "options": ["Linux", "Norton", "Avast", "Nood32"],
      "correct_answer": "Linux"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি স্থায়ী Storage device?",
      "options": ["RAM", "Cash Memory", "SSD", "CPU Register"],
      "correct_answer": "SSD"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি System Unit এর অংশ নয়?",
      "options": ["Processor", "RAM", "Hard Disk Drive", "Flash Drive"],
      "correct_answer": "Flash Drive"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "Projector Enable করার Keyboard Command কী?",
      "options": [
        "Windows Key + P",
        "Windows Key + V",
        "Windows Key + C",
        "Window Key + R"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Windows Key + P"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "A4 size  এর কাগজ কোনটি?",
      "options": ["8.5” X 11”", "8.27” X 11.69”", "8.5” X 14”"],
      "correct_answer": "8.27” X 11.69”"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি Document Copy করার Keyboard Command?",
      "options": ["Ctrl + P", "Ctrl + C", "Ctrl + V", "Ctrl + X"],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl + C"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি Page Break এর Keyboard Command?",
      "options": ["Ctrl + Break", "Ctrl + End", "Ctrl + Enter", "Ctrl + Space"],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl + Enter"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি Ms-Word এর Extention?",
      "options": [".docx", ".doc", ".exe", ".xlsx"],
      "correct_answer": ".docx"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "একই Formatting একাধিক Text এঁর উপর Apply করতে নিচের কোন অপশনটি ব্যবহার করতে হয়?",
      "options": [
        "Copy and Paste old Text",
        "Copy and Paste",
        "Use Format Painter",
        "Use Clipboard"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Use Format Painter"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোন Line Spacing টি অগ্রহণযোগ্য?",
      "options": ["Multiple", "Double", "Triple", "None of the above"],
      "correct_answer": "Multiple"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি Excel এর Valid Data টাইপ নয় কোনটি?",
      "options": ["Date/Time", "Label", "Character", "Charter"],
      "correct_answer": "Charter"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "Excel window এর কোন area তে value ও formula লেখা যায়?",
      "options": ["Formula Bar", "Menu Bar", "Title Bar", "Side Bar"],
      "correct_answer": "Formula Bar"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "Row নং 5 ও 6 এর column C হতে E পর্যন্ত cell গুলোকে যোগ করার সময় নিচের কোনটি করতে হয়?",
      "options": ["=Sum(c5:e6)", "=Total(c5:e5)", "=Sum(c5:e5)", "Sum(c5:e6)"],
      "correct_answer": "=Sum(c5:e6)"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "Current Date display করার জন্য কোন Function ব্যবহার করতে হয়?",
      "options": ["Date()", "Now()", "Today()", "Current()"],
      "correct_answer": "Now()"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোনটি formula এর উদাহরণ?",
      "options": ["=sum(A5:A7)", "sum(A5:A7)", "=A5+A6+A7", "=sum(A5+A6+A7)"],
      "correct_answer": "=sum(A5:A7)"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "কোন Function টি শর্ত সাপেক্ষে কাজ করে?",
      "options": ["Min()", "Count()", "Sumif()", "Max()"],
      "correct_answer": "Sumif()"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "পূর্বে তৈরী করা কোনো Presentation শুরু করার শর্টকাট হলো?",
      "options": ["Ctrl+O", "Ctrl+M", "Ctrl+N", "Ctrl+G"],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl+N"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "Power Point এ নতুন প্রেজেন্টেশন তৈরির শর্টকাট হল",
      "options": ["Ctrl+N", "Ctrl+M", "Shift+N", "Shift+G"],
      "correct_answer": "Ctrl+N"
    },
    {
      "question_set": "Set New 7",
      "question": "Upper case character সমূহ টাইপ করার জন্য কোন key ব্যবহার করা হয়?",
      "options": ["Alt", "Ctrl", "Esc", "CapsLock"],
      "correct_answer": "CapsLock"
    }
  ]
  